<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The charter of the Royal Lustring Company</title>
            <author>Royal Lustring Company (London, England)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1697</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 47 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 7 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A79427</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C3725</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R230945</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99896600</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99896600</idno>
            <idno type="VID">134626</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A79427)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 134626)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2424:15)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The charter of the Royal Lustring Company</title>
                  <author>Royal Lustring Company (London, England)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[1], 4-10 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[S.l. :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1697]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Date of publication from Wing (CD-ROM edition).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Lincoln's Inn Library, London.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Royal Lustring Company (London, England) --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Commerce --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-09</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-09</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="charter">
            <pb facs="tcp:134626:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>THE CHARTER OF THE Royal Luſtring Company.</head>
            <opener>
               <signed>
                  <hi>
                     <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>ILLIAM</hi> and <hi>MARY</hi> by the Grace of God, King and Queen of <hi>England, Scotland, France</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> Defenders of the Faith, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </signed>
               <salute>To all to whom theſe Preſents ſhall come, Greeting:</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <hi>Whereas,</hi> Our well beloved Subjects <hi>Paul Cloudeſly, Peter Lekeux</hi> and <hi>Hillary Renew,</hi> on behalf of themſelves and ſeveral others, have by their hum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Petition repreſented unto us, That they have, with great Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pence and Induſtry attained to the New Invention of Making, Dreſſing, and Luſtrating of Silks called plain black <hi>Allamodes, Renforces</hi> and <hi>Luſtrings,</hi> and have already cauſed to be made great Quantities of the ſaid Silks, at leaſt equal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling the Manufacture of <hi>France,</hi> as well in Luſtre as otherwiſe, for the ſole Uſe, Exer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciſe, and Benefit, of which ſaid Invention, the ſaid <hi>Paul Cloudeſly,</hi> together with <hi>William Sherrard,</hi> and alſo <hi>Peter Du-cloux</hi> (who is ſince gone into Parts beyond the Seas) obtained of the late King <hi>James</hi> II. Letters Patents bearing date the Three and Twentieth Day of <hi>November,</hi> in the Fourth Year of his Reign, for the Term of Four<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teen Years from the Day of the Date of the ſaid Letters Patents:<note place="margin">King <hi>James</hi>'s Patent to Mr. <hi>Cloudeſley</hi> and Company re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cited. <hi>4. Jac. 11.</hi>
               </note> 
               <hi>And whereas</hi> they have alſo informed us, That they are further Reſolved Induſtriouſly to promote the ſaid Work to the Honour and Common Good of this Nation, by Imploying many Thouſands of Poor People, as well in Working the ſaid Silks, as by other Dependen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies upon the ſame; as alſo by ſaving the vaſt Expences of Money that uſed to be ſent Yearly into <hi>France</hi> for the ſaid Commodities; And have humbly beſought us to Incor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>porate them and divers others hereafter mentioned to Manage and Carry on the ſame by a Joynt-Stock: <hi>Know ye therefore,</hi> That We being deſirous to promote all En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavours tending to the Publick Good of this Our Kingdom, and to encourage ſo com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mendable an Undertaking, of Our eſpecial Grace, certain Knowledge and meer Moti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, Have Given, Granted, Conſtituted, Declared, and Appointed, and by theſe Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſents for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, do Give, Grant, Conſtitute, Declare, and Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>point, That Our Right Truſty, and Right well-beloved Couſin and Counſellour, <hi>Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas</hi> Earl of <hi>Pembrooke</hi> and <hi>Montgomery,</hi> the ſaid <hi>Paul Cloudeſly, William Sherrard, Peter Lekeux;</hi> and alſo Our Truſty and well-beloved <hi>John Blondell, Lewis Ger<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vaize,
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:134626:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>Peter Lauze, Stephen Noguier, Paul Rey, John Lekeux, Peter Floyer, Thomas Blythe, Joſeph Paice, Robert Hackſhaw, Edward Lloyd, William Groſvenor, Richard Cooper,</hi> and <hi>Hillary Renew,</hi> and ſuch others as ſhall be admitted into the ſaid Society, from henceforth be, and ſhall be One Body Corporate and Politick in Deed and in Name, by the Name of the <hi>Royal Luſtring Company</hi> for Making and Dreſſing of <hi>Allamodes, Renforces</hi> and <hi>Luſtrings</hi> in <hi>England:</hi>
               <note place="margin">The Earl of <hi>Pembrooke</hi> and <hi>17</hi> Perſons more and their Succeſſours are Incorporated for ever by the name of <hi>The Royal Luſtring Company.</hi>
               </note> And them by the Name of the <hi>Royal Luſtring Company,</hi> We do for the purpoſe aforeſaid really and fully for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, Make, Erect, Ordain, Conſtitute, Eſtabliſh, Confirm, and Declare by theſe Preſents to be one Body Corporate and Politick in Deed and in Name for ever, for the Making and Dreſſing of <hi>Alamodes, Renforces,</hi> and <hi>Luſtrings</hi> in <hi>England,</hi> according to the Tenour of the aforeſaid Letters Patents, and that by the ſame Name of the <hi>Royal Luſtring Company,</hi> for Making and Dreſſing of <hi>Allamodes, Renforces,</hi> and <hi>Luſtrings</hi> in <hi>England,</hi> they ſhall have perpetual Succeſſion, and that they and their Succeſſors by the Name of the <hi>Royal Luſtring Company</hi> for Making and Dreſſing of <hi>Allamodes, Renforces,</hi> and <hi>Luſtrings</hi> in <hi>England</hi> be, and at all times hereafter ſhall be Perſons Able and Capable in Law to Have, Purchaſe, Receive, Enjoy and Retain Lands, Rents, Privileges, Liberties, Fran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chiſes and Hereditaments of what Kind, Nature, and Quality ſoever they be, to them and their Succeſſors;<note place="margin">The Company (by the ſame Name) may Buy and Sell Land, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </note> and alſo to Give, Grant, Alien, Aſſign and Diſpoſe of Lands, Tenements, and Hereditaments, and to Do and Execute all and ſingular other things by the ſame Name that to them ſhall, or may Appertain to do. <hi>And</hi> that they and their Succeſſors by the Name of the <hi>Royal Luſtring Company</hi> for Making and Dreſſing of <hi>Allamodes, Renfor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces,</hi> and <hi>Luſtrings</hi> in <hi>England,</hi>
               <note place="margin">The Company may Plead and be Impleaded in any Courts, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </note> may Plead and be Impleaded, Anſwer, and be Anſwered unto, Defend and be Defended in whatſoever Courts and Places, and before any Judges, Juſtices or Officers of Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, in all, and ſingular Actions, Pleas, Suits, Plaints, Matters and Demands of what Kind or Quality ſoever they ſhall be in the ſame Manner and Form, and as fully and amply as any of Our Subjects of this Our Realm of <hi>England,</hi> may or can, do Plead, or be Impleaded, Anſwer, and be Anſwered unto, Defend and be Defended: <hi>And</hi> that the ſaid <hi>Royal Luſtring Company</hi> for Making and Dreſſing of <hi>Allamodes, Renforces,</hi> and <hi>Luſtrings</hi> in <hi>England,</hi> and their Succeſſors may have a common Seal for the Expedition of the Buſineſs and Affairs of the ſaid Company;<note place="margin">The Company may have a Common Seal, which they may break, alter, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> or make anew as they ſhall think fit. One of the Company ſhall be Governour.</note> 
               <hi>And</hi> that it ſhall and may be lawful for them and their Succeſſors, the ſame Seal from Time to Time at their Wills and Pleaſures, to Break, Change, Alter, or Make anew, as to them ſhall ſeem expedient. <hi>And further,</hi> We will, and by theſe Preſents, for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, do Ordain, that there ſhall be from henceforth one of the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany to be Elected and Appointed in ſuch Manner and Form as hereafter in theſe Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſents is Directed, Mentioned, and Expreſſed, who ſhall be, and be called Governour of the ſaid Company: And there ſhall alſo be from henceforth a Deputy-Governour and Twelve Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Company,<note place="margin">There ſhall be a Deputy-Governour and <hi>12</hi> Aſſiſtants.</note> to be Elected and Appointed in ſuch Manner and Form as hereafter in theſe Preſents is Directed, Mentioned, and Expreſſed, for the Mana<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging and Carrying on all Buſineſs and Affairs belonging to the ſaid Company: <hi>And</hi> we do hereby Nominate, Make, and Ordain the ſaid <hi>Thomas</hi> Earl of <hi>Pembrook</hi> and <hi>Mont<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gomery,</hi> to be the Firſt and Preſent Governour of the ſaid Company,<note place="margin">The Earl of <hi>Pembrooke</hi> Nominated Governour, to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinue till another of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany be Choſen and Sworn.</note> to continue in the ſaid Office of Governour from the Date of theſe Preſents, until another of the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany in due Manner be Choſen and Sworn into the ſaid Office according to the Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nances and Proviſions hereafter in theſe Preſents Expreſſed and Declared, if the ſaid <hi>Thomas</hi> Earl of <hi>Pembrook</hi> and <hi>Montgomery</hi> ſhall ſo long live: <hi>And alſo</hi> We have Aſſigned, Named and Appointed, and by theſe Preſents for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, We do Aſſign,<note place="margin">Mr. <hi>Peter Lekeux</hi> Depu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty-Governour until the <hi>25th.</hi> of <hi>Jan. 1692/3.</hi> &amp;c.</note> Nominate, Conſtitute, and Make the ſaid <hi>Peter Lekeux</hi> to be the Firſt and Preſent Deputy-Governour of the ſaid Company, to continue in the ſaid Office of De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puty-Governour until the Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>January</hi> next enſuing the Date of theſe Our Letters Patents, and from and after that Time, until ſome other fit Perſon ſhall be duly Elected and Sworn into the ſaid Office of Deputy-Governour of the ſaid Compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny, if the ſaid <hi>Peter Lekeux</hi> ſhall ſo long live: <hi>And</hi> Our further Will and Pleaſure is, and We do hereby for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, Direct and Appoint, That from and after the ſaid Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>January</hi> next enſuing, or the Election of ſome other fit Perſon into the ſaid Office of Deputy-Governour of the ſaid Company, the ſaid <hi>Peter Lekeux</hi> ſhall be and continue an Aſſiſtant of the ſaid Company until the Five and Twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tieth Day of <hi>January,</hi>
               <note place="margin">That from the <hi>25th.</hi> of <hi>Jan. 1692/3.</hi> or new Election, <hi>Peter Lekeux</hi> ſhall be an Aſſiſtant until the <hi>25th.</hi> of <hi>Jan. 1696, &amp;c.</hi>
               </note> which ſhall be in the Year of our Lord, One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety and Six, and from that Time, until ſome other fit Perſon ſhall be Elected and Sworn an Aſſiſtant of the ſaid Company in his Stead, if he ſhall ſo long live, and We have Conſtituted, Nominated, and Appointed, and by theſe Preſents, for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, do Conſtitute, Nominate, and Appoint the ſaid <hi>John Blondel, Lewis Gervaize,</hi>
               <note place="margin">
                  <hi>Meſſ.</hi> Blondell, Gervaize. Claudeſly, Sherrard, Lauze,</note> 
               <hi>Paul Clowdeſly, William Sherrard, Peter Lauze, Stephen Noguier, Paul Rey,
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:134626:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>John Lekeux, Peter Floyer, Joſeph Paice, William Groſvenor,</hi> and <hi>Robert Hackſhaw,</hi>
               <note place="margin">Noguier. Rey. John Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>keux, Floyer, Paice. Groſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venor, <hi>and</hi> Hackſhaw <hi>Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants.</hi>
               </note> to be the Firſt and Preſent Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Company, the ſaid <hi>John Blondel, Lewis Gervaize, Paul Cloudeſly, William Sherrard, Peter Lauze, Stephen Noguier,</hi> and <hi>Paul Rey,</hi> to continue in their ſaid Offices of Aſſiſtants, until the ſaid Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>January,</hi> which ſhall be in the Year of Our Lord, One Thouſand, Six Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred,<note place="margin">The firſt Seven to continue till the <hi>25th.</hi> of <hi>January, 1696,</hi> &amp;c.</note> Ninety and Six, and from and after that Time, until ſome other fit Perſons ſhall be duly Elected and Sworn into their ſaid Offices of Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Company,<note place="margin">The other Five till the <hi>25th.</hi> of <hi>January, 1696.</hi>
               </note> if they ſhall ſo long live, and the ſaid <hi>John Lekeux,</hi> and <hi>Peter Floyer, Joſeph Paice, William Groſvenor,</hi> and <hi>Robert Hackſhaw,</hi> to continue in their ſaid Office of Aſſiſtants until the Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>January</hi> next enſuing the Date hereof, and from, and after that Time, until ſome other fit Perſons ſhall be duly Elected and Sworn into their ſaid Offices of Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Company, if they ſhall ſo long live: <hi>And further,</hi> We do hereby for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors,<note place="margin">The Company have Power upon the <hi>25th.</hi> of <hi>Jan. 1692/3.</hi> or within <hi>14</hi> Days after to chuſe five Perſons out of the ſaid Meſſ. <hi>Floyer, Lekeux, Blithe, Paice, Hackſhaw Lloyd, Groſvenor,</hi> and <hi>Cooper,</hi> to be Aſſiſtants till the <hi>25th.</hi> of <hi>Jan. 1693,</hi> &amp;c.</note> Give and Grant unto the ſaid Company, and their Succeſſors, or the Major Part of them, full Power and Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority upon the ſaid Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>January</hi> next enſuing, or within Fourteen Days after, to Elect and Chuſe Five Perſons out of the before-named <hi>Peter Floyer, John Lekeux, Thomas Blithe, Joſeph Paice, Robert Hackſhaw, Edward Lloyd, William Groſvenor,</hi> and <hi>Richard Cooper,</hi> who ſhall be, and continue Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Company, from the Time of their Election, until the Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>January,</hi> which ſhall be in the Year of our Lord, One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety and Three, and from thence until ſome other fit Perſons ſhall be duly Ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted and Sworn into their ſaid Offices of Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Company: <hi>And likewiſe,</hi> We do by theſe Preſents, for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, Give and Grant unto the ſaid Company and their Succeſſors, or the Major Part of them, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of the Governour, or in his Abſence the Deputy-Governour,<note place="margin">The Company have Power, upon the <hi>25th.</hi> of <hi>Jan. 1693.</hi> or within <hi>14</hi> Days after and ſo yearly till the <hi>25th.</hi> of <hi>Jan. 1696.</hi> to chuſe five Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons of the Company having <hi>10</hi> Shares a piece at leaſt to be Aſſiſtants.</note> and in the Abſence of the Governour and Deputy-Governour, the Treaſurer of the ſaid Company for the Time being, to be always one full Power and Authority, upon the ſaid Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>January,</hi> which ſhall be in the Year of our Lord, One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety and Three, or within Fourteen Days after, and ſo Yearly, and every Year, up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on every Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>January</hi> following, or within Fourteen Days after until the Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>January,</hi> which ſhall be in the Year of our Lord, One Thouſand, Six Hundred, Ninety and Six, to Elect and Chuſe Five Perſons, being Members of the ſaid Company, and have each of them Ten Shares at leaſt in the Joint-Stock of the ſaid Company, who after they are duly Sworn into their Offices, ſhall be and continue Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Company, from the Time of their Election, until the Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>January,</hi> then next following, and from thence, until ſome other fit Perſons ſhall be duly Elected, and Sworn into their ſaid Offices of Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Company. <hi>And</hi> We have further Given and Granted, and by theſe Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſents, for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, do Give and Grant to the ſaid Company and their Succeſſors, full Power and Authority, That they the ſaid Governour and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany, and their Succeſſors, or the Major Part of them, whereof the Governour, or in his Abſence, the Deputy-Governour, and in the Abſence of the Governour and Depu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty-Governour, the Treaſurer of the ſaid Company (for the Time being) to be one, on the ſaid Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>January</hi> Yearly, or within Fourteen Days after,<note place="margin">The Company ſhall on the <hi>25th.</hi> of <hi>Jan.</hi> yearly, or with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in <hi>14</hi> Days after, Chuſe out of the then Aſſiſtants two fit Perſons to be Governour and Deputy-Governour to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinue for <hi>1</hi> Year.</note> ſhall, and may Elect and Chuſe out of the Then Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Company, Two fit Perſons to be Governour and Deputy-Governour of the ſaid Company, who ſhall continue in their ſaid Offices for one whole Year next following ſuch their Election, and from thence, till ſome other fit Perſons ſhall be duly Elected and Sworn into the ſaid Offices of Governour and Deputy-Governour of the ſaid Company. <hi>And further,</hi> We do by theſe Preſents, for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, Give and Grant to the ſaid Company and their Succeſſors, or the Major Part of them (for the Time being) whereof the Governour, and in his Abſence the Deputy-Governour, and in the Abſence of the Governour and Deputy-Governour, the Treaſurer of the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany (for the Time being) to be one full Power and Authority to Elect and Chuſe upon the ſaid Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>January,</hi> which ſhall be in the Year of our Lord,<note place="margin">The Company have Power, on the <hi>25th.</hi> of <hi>Jan. 1696,</hi> or within <hi>14.</hi> Days after and ſo upon every <hi>25th,</hi> of <hi>Jan.</hi> following, or within <hi>14</hi> Days, after for ever to Chuſe <hi>12</hi> Aſſiſtants, (beſides the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernour and Deputy) having <hi>10</hi> Shares apiece at leaſt.</note> One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety and Six, or within Fourteen Days after, and ſo on every Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>January</hi> following, or within Fourteen Days after, forever. Twelve Perſons beſides the Governour and Deputy-Governour of the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany, having Ten Shares a piece at leaſt in the Joint Stock of the ſaid Company, who ſhall be Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Company for one whole Year next following ſuch Election or Elections, and from thence till ſome other fit Perſons ſhall be duly Elected and Sworn in their Stead. <hi>And</hi> We do hereby for Us, our Heirs and Succeſſors,<note place="margin">None ſhall be Governour, Deputy or Aſſiſtants (except the Perſons before particular<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Named) who have not <hi>10</hi> Shares at leaſt.</note> Direct and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand that no Perſon or Perſons whatſoever, except ſuch as are before in theſe Preſents
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:134626:3" rendition="simple:additions"/>particularly Named and Conſtituted, ſhall at any time hereafter be admitted to the Office of Governour, Deputy-Governour, or Aſſiſtant of the ſaid Company, who hath not Ten Shares at leaſt in the Joint-Stock of the ſaid Company. <hi>And</hi> Our Will and Pleaſure is, and We do hereby for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, Declare and Grant to the ſaid Company,<note place="margin">If Meſſ. <hi>Cloudeſley, Sher<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rard, Peter Lekeux, Blon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dell, Gervaize, Lauze, Noguier</hi> and <hi>Rey,</hi> or any of them ſhall dye <hi>&amp;c.</hi> or leave this Realm, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> before the <hi>25th.</hi> of <hi>Jan. 1696.</hi> Then the Company may chuſe others in their Place out of Meſſ. <hi>John Lekeux, Floyer, Groſve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor Blithe, Paice, Hack<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhaw, Lloyd</hi> and <hi>Cooper,</hi> to continue till the <hi>25th.</hi> of <hi>Jan. 1696.</hi>
               </note> and their Succeſſors now, and for the Time being; That if it ſhall happen that any of them the ſaid <hi>Paul Clowdeſley, William Sherrard, Peter Lekeux, John Blondel, Lewis Gervaize, Peter Lauze, Stephen Noguier,</hi> and <hi>Paul Rey</hi> ſhall die, or leave this Realm, or be permitted to Surrender his or their Office, or Offices of Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtant, or Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Company, at any Time before the ſaid Five and Twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tieth Day of <hi>January,</hi> One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety and Six, it ſhall and may be lawful for the ſaid Governour and Company, and their Succeſſors, or the Major Part of them, whereof the Governour, and in his Abſence the Deputy-Governour, and in the Abſence of the Governour and Deputy-Governour, the Treaſurer of the ſaid Company) for the Time being) to be one to Chuſe one or more other, or others out of the aforenamed <hi>John Lekeux, Peter Floyer, William Groſvenor, Thomas Blithe, Joſeph Paice, Robert Hackſhaw, Edward Lloyd</hi> and <hi>Richard Cooper</hi> into the Place or Places of him or them ſo dying, departing this Kingdom, or being permitted to ſurrender his or their Office or Offices; which ſaid Perſon or Perſons after being duly Sworn, ſhall be and conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nue and Aſſiſtant or Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Company, until the ſaid Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>January,</hi> One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety and Six; and from thence until ſome other Perſon or Perſons ſhall be duly Elected and Sworn in his or their ſtead. <hi>And</hi> We do hereby for Us,<note place="margin">The Company may keep a Court when and where they pleaſe.</note> Our Heirs and Succeſſors, Give and Grant unto the ſaid Company, and their Succeſſors, full Power and Authority to hold, and keep a Court in ſome Hall or Place, or Places within Our Cities of <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> or either of them, or in any other Part of this our Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> or Dominion of <hi>Wales,</hi> and there to aſſemble, and meet together ſo often as they ſhall ſee Cauſe, to Treat and Conſult con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning the Affairs of the ſaid Company.<note place="margin">The Governour, Deputy, and Aſſiſtants or any <hi>7</hi> or more of them ſhall be a Committee, who may as of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten at they Pleaſe Chuſe Treaſurer, Secretaries and all other under Officers.</note> 
               <hi>And</hi> we do hereby for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, Grant and Declare, That the ſaid Governour, Deputy-Governour, and Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants, or any Seven, or more of them, whereof the Governour, Deputy-Governour, or Treaſurer (for the time being) to be one be, and ſhall be called the Committee of the ſaid Company, and that it ſhall be Lawful for the ſaid Committee from time to time, and ſo often as they ſhall ſee cauſe to Chuſe and Appoint a Treaſurer, or Treaſurers, Secretaries, Book-keepers, Clerks, Beadles, or other under Officers neceſſary for the Service of the ſaid Company: And to Conſtitute, Ordain, and make ſuch, and ſo many reaſonable Laws, Orders, and Ordinances as to them, or the greater Part of them being then and there preſent, ſhall ſeem neceſſary and convenient for the well Ordering and Government of the ſaid Company,<note place="margin">The Committee or the Major part to make and alter Laws, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to Puniſh, and Fine, and Mitigate.</note> and the ſaid Laws, Orders, and Ordinances, or any of them to alter and annul as the ſaid Committee ſhall ſee requiſite, and to ſet, impoſe, and inflict reaſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nable Pains, Puniſhments, and Penalties by Fines, and Amerciaments upon any Offender or Offenders, who ſhall Tranſgreſs, Break, or Violate the ſaid Laws, Orders, or Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nances ſo made as aforeſaid, and to mitigate the ſame as they ſhall find Cauſe; which ſaid Fines, Penalties, and Amerciaments ſhall, and may be Levied, Sued for, Taken, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained and Recovered by the ſaid Governour and Company,<note place="margin">The Company or their Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers or Servants may Levy Fines by Diſtreſs or Action of Debt.</note> or their Succeſſors, or by their Officers and Servants from time to time, to be appointed for that purpoſe, by Diſtreſs, or Action of Debt, or by any other Lawful Ways or Means to the Uſe and Advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage of the Governour and Company,<note place="margin">The Charter requires the Company's Laws to be obſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved ſo as the ſame be Reaſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nable and not Contrary to the Laws of this Realm.</note> and their Succeſſors, without any Account to be rendred for the ſame to Us, our Heirs and Succeſſors, all, and ſingular, which Laws, Conſtitutions, Orders, and Ordinances ſo as aforeſaid to be made, We will to be duly ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerved and kept under the Pains and Penalties therein to be contained ſo always, as the ſaid Laws,<note place="margin">The Governour, Deputy, and Aſſiſtants, or the Major part (whereof the Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, Deputy, or Treaſurer to be One) may as often as they pleaſe Appoint Sub-Committees, and call toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther the Officers and Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers to Courts and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittees, to Conſult of the Company's Affairs, and to put their By-Laws in Execution.</note> Conſtitutions, Orders and Ordinances, Fines, and Amerciaments be reaſonable, and not contrary or repugnant to the Laws or Statutes of this Our Realm: <hi>And farther,</hi> For Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, We do Grant unto the ſaid Company, and their Succeſſors, That it ſhall, and may be Lawful to, and for the ſaid Governour, Deputy-Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernour and Aſſiſtants, and their Succeſſors, or the Major part of them; The Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, Deputy-Governour, or Treaſurer being always one, ſo often as they ſhall think neceſſary to appoint Sub-Committees, and to Summon and Call together the Officers and Members of the ſaid Company (for the time being) to ſuch Courts and Committees, as well in <hi>London,</hi>
               <note place="margin">The Governour, or De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puty, ſhall, Yearly hold a Court on or about the <hi>25th.</hi> of <hi>Jan.</hi> in order to the Election of Governour, De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puty and Aſſiſtants, and ſhall give Publick Notice <hi>10</hi> Days before Election.</note> as in any other place or places within our Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> or Dominion of <hi>Wales,</hi> to Treat and Conſult concerning the Affairs of the ſaid Company, and to put their By-Laws in Execution, in any part or parts of our ſaid Dominions: <hi>And</hi> We do hereby for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, Declare our Will and Pleaſure to be, That the Governour, or Deputy-Governour, for the time being, do, and ſhall Yearly,<note place="margin">Every Member having <hi>10</hi> Shares or more may Deliver, or ſend his Vote in Writing when he ſhall have <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>im<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> Notice. All Votes for Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernour, Deputy and Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſtants ſhall be in Writing and Examined in open Court, the Governour, Deputy and the Major part of the Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants being preſent. None ſhall Vote who hath not <hi>10</hi> Shares. None to have more than One Vote for all the Shares he hath. And if there happen Equality of Votes, the Governour and in his abſence the Deputy ſhall have the Caſting Vote.</note> and every Year, hold, and call a Court, on or about the ſaid Five and Twentieth
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:134626:3" rendition="simple:additions"/>Day of <hi>January,</hi> in order to the Election of a Governour, Deputy-Governour, and Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants in Manner and Form, as is before expreſſed, and ſhall give Publick Notice of the ſame Ten Days before every ſuch Election or Elections: <hi>And</hi> We do hereby alſo for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, Grant, and Ordain that every Member of the ſaid Company having Ten Shares, or more in the Joynt-Stock, may deliver or ſend his Vote in Wri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting, whenſoever he ſhall have due and timely Notice of ſuch Election or Elections, and that all Votes in every Election of a Governour, Deputy-Governour, and Aſſiſtants ſhall be delivered, or ſent in Writing, and ſhall be peruſed and examined in open Court. The Governour or Deputy-Governour, and Major part of the Aſſiſtants being preſent, and that no Perſon ſhall be admitted to Vote, who hath not Ten Shares in the Joint-Stock of the ſaid Company, and no Perſon to have more than one Vote for all the Shares he hath in the ſaid Joynt-Stock, and whenever there ſhall happen to be equality of Votes in Ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction of any Officers or Members of the ſaid Company, the ſaid Governour,<note place="margin">That None ſhall be Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted into any Office till he hath taken in open Court be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Governour, Deputy or Treaſurer the Oaths Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed by the Act <hi>Primo Willielmi &amp; Mariae,</hi> inti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tuled, And Act for Abrogating the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance, and Appointing other Oath; and alſo an Oath for the due Execution of his Office.</note> and in his Abſence, the Deputy-Governour for the time being ſhall have the Caſting-Vote, and that no Perſon ſhall be admitted into any Office belonging to the ſaid Company, until he hath firſt taken in open Court, before the Governour, Deputy-Governour, or Treaſurer of the ſaid Company, the Oaths appointed by Act of Parliament made in the Firſt Year of Our Reign, Intitled, <hi>An Act for Abrogating the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance, and Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointing other Oaths, and alſo an Oath for the due Execution of his or their Office or Offices, and Truſt, and faithful Obſervance of the Laws, Conſtitutions, Orders, and Ordinances of the ſaid Company:</hi> To which Governor, Deputy-Governor, or Treaſurer, for the time being, We do hereby for us, our Heirs, and Succeſſors,<note place="margin">Authority to the Governor, Deputy, or Treaſurer to Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miniſter the Oaths.</note> give full Power and Authority to adminiſter ſuch Oaths accordingly: <hi>And further,</hi> Our Will and Pleaſure is, that every Perſon who, being duly elected into the Office of Governor,<note place="margin">Every Perſon being duly Elected Governor, Deputy, or Aſſiſtant, who ſhall within <hi>14</hi> Days after his Election refuſe to take upon him his Office or the Oaths, ſhall pay to the Company ſuch Fines as by their Laws ſhall be Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed, and other Perſons ſhall be choſen in their Places.</note> Deputy-Governor, or Aſſiſtant of the ſaid Company, ſhall within Fourteen Days after his Election, Refuſe to take upon him the Office or Place whereunto he ſhall be elected as aforeſaid, or to take any, or either of the ſaid Oaths ſo ordered and appointed to be taken by the Governor, Deputy-Governor, or Aſſiſtants, ſhall forfeit and pay to the Governor and Company, and their Succeſſors, ſuch Fines and Amerciaments, as by the Laws aforeſaid ſhall be directed, limited, and appointed, and other Perſon and Perſons ſhall be Choſen and Elected into his or their Place and Places. <hi>And further,</hi>
               <note place="margin">The Company or the Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor Part in Court have Power to diſplace any Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernor, Deputy, Aſſiſtant, or other Officer, for Miſde<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>meanor, or any reaſonable Cauſe, and to Elect others in their Place.</note> We do for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, Give and Grant unto the ſaid Company, and their Succeſſors, or the Major Part of them in Court aſſembled, full Power and Authority to remove, and diſplace any Governor, Deputy-Governor, Aſſiſtant, or any other Officer of the ſaid Company, for Miſdemeanour, or any other reaſonable Cauſe, and to Elect others in the Place or Places of the Perſon of Perſons ſo removed; and that as often as it ſhall happen, that the Governor, or Deputy-Governor,<note place="margin">That if the Governor, De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puty, or any of the Aſſiſtants ſhall die, or be permitted to Surrender their Offices and that there be a Vacancy, all who have ten Shares, upon timely Notice by the Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor or Deputy may chuſe others in their Room to conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nue till the <hi>25th</hi> of <hi>Jan.</hi> then following, firſt taking the Oaths as aforeſaid.</note> or any of the Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants of the ſaid Company (for the time being) ſhall die, or ſhall be permitted by the Governor, or Deputy-Governor, and Major Part of the Aſſiſtants, in open Court, to ſurrender his or their Office or Offices, and that there ſhall happen to be any Vacancy of a Governor, Deputy-Governor, or Aſſiſtant of the ſaid Company, That it ſhall and may be lawful to, and for all ſuch Perſons who have Ten Shares in the ſaid Joynt-Stock, timely Notice being given to them by the Governor or Deputy-Governor of ſuch Death or Vacancy, to Chuſe and Elect into his or their Place or Places ſome other Perſon or Perſons of the ſaid Company for Governor, Deputy-Governor, or Aſſiſtant, by the Methods, Manner, and Limitations herein before appointed, mentioned, and expreſſed, the ſaid Governor, Deputy-Governor or Aſſiſtant to continue in his or their Office or Offices till the Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>January,</hi> then next following his or their Election, and till ſome other Perſon or Perſons ſhall be Elected and Sworn into his or their Office or Offices, he or they having firſt in open Court taken the Oaths appointed to be taken by the Governor, Deputy-Governor, and Aſſiſtants, before their Admittance into their reſpective Offices, and in the Manner aforeſaid.<note place="margin">If any Member that hath or ſhall agree by Writing un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der his Hand to Adventure or pay in Money towards the Joint-Stock, and ſhall not within ten Days after Warn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing bring in the ſame, that then the Company or the Major Part (whereof the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernor or Deputy to be one) at a General Court to disfranchiſe ſuch Members.</note> 
               <hi>And</hi> of Our more abundant Grace and Favour to the ſaid Governor and Company, We do here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by declare Our Will and Pleaſure to be, That if it ſhall ſo happen that any of the Perſons herein before particularly Named, or who ſhall hereafter become Members of the ſaid Company, who hath Promiſed and Agreed, or ſhall Promiſe or Agree by Wri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting, under his or their Hands or Hands, to Adventure, or to pay in any Sum or Sums of Money towards the Joynt-Stock of the ſaid Company, and ſhall not within Ten Days next, after Warning given to him or them, bring in, and deliver to the Treaſurer appoin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted by the Company ſuch Sum or Sums of Money as ſhall have been expreſſed or ſet down in Writing, and Subſcribed by the ſaid Perſon or Perſons, that then, and at all times after it, ſhall and may be Lawful to and for the ſaid Governor and Company, or the Major Part of them preſent, whereof the ſaid Governor, or Deputy-Governor to be
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:134626:4" rendition="simple:additions"/>one, at any of their General Courts or Aſſemblies, to Remove and Disfranchiſe ſuch Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or Perſons from and out of the ſaid Corporation or Company, ſo refuſing to Pay, or Anſwer his or their Subſcription Money.<note place="margin">The Earl of <hi>Pembrook</hi> is required to take the Oaths before Meſſ. <hi>Peter Lekeux, Blondel,</hi> and <hi>Gervaize,</hi> or any two of them.</note> 
               <hi>And further,</hi> Our Will and Pleaſure is, and We do alſo hereby Ordain, That the ſaid <hi>Thomas</hi> Earl of <hi>Pembrook</hi> and <hi>Montgomery,</hi> herein before-named, to be Governor of the ſaid Company, ſhall take his Corporal Oath before the ſaid <hi>Peter Lekeux, John Blondel,</hi> and <hi>Lewis Gervaize,</hi> or any Two of them; and the aforeſaid ſeveral Perſons herein before-named, to be the preſent Deputy-Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor and Aſſiſtants of the ſaid Company,<note place="margin">The preſent Deputy and Aſſiſtants ſhall take the Oaths before the preſent Governor and Company, or the Major Part in Publick Court.</note> ſhall take their Corporal Oaths before the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Governor of the ſaid Company in ſuch Manner and Form, as by the Governor and Company, or the greater Part of them in any Publick Court to be held for the ſaid Company, ſhall be Lawfully and Reaſonably ſet down and deviſed, To whom ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rally and reſpectively We do hereby for Us, our Heirs and Succeſſors, Give full Power and Authority to adminiſter the ſaid Oaths to the ſaid Officers accordingly. <hi>And</hi> We do hereby further for Us,<note place="margin">All Judges, Juſtices, and other Officers are Comman<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded to Favour and Aid the Company.</note> Our Heirs and Succeſſors. Will, Authorize, and Command all and ſingular our Judges, Juſtices of the Peace, Mayors, Sheriffs, Bailiffs, Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables, Headboroughs, and all other the Officers and Miniſters whatſoever, of Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors now (and for the time being) within this our Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> and Dominion of <hi>Wales,</hi> That they, and every of them reſpectively be from time to time in their ſeveral and reſpective Offices, Favouring, Aiding, Furthering, Helping and Aſſiſting unto the ſaid Governour and Company, and their Succeſſors, their Agents and Servants in all things, according to Our Royal Will and Pleaſure herein before declared. <hi>And</hi> of our further Eſpecial Grace, Certain Knowledge, and meer Motion for the carrying on, and promoting the Intereſt of the Company aforeſaid, We have given and granted, and by theſe Preſents for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, do Give and Grant unto the ſaid Company, and their Succeſſors, That they the ſaid Governour and Company, and their Succeſſors, ſhall and may be hereafter Perſons able and capable to have, and We do by theſe preſent for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, Grant that they ſhall and may have Full, Free, and Lawful Licence, Power, and Authority to Take, Have, Purchaſe, Receive, Enjoy,<note place="margin">The Company may pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſe Lands and Heredita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, not exceeding <hi>1000</hi>l. <hi>per Annum.</hi> above all Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges and Reprizes.</note> and Poſſeſs to them and their Succeſſors for ever any Manners Lordſhips, Meſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuages, Mills, Waters, Streams, Rents, Services, Reverſions, Lands, Mines, Tenements, and other Hereditaments whatſoever, ſo as the ſame Mannors, Meſſuages, Lordſhips, Mills, Waters, Streams, Rents, Services, Reverſions, Lands, Tenements, and other Hereditaments do not exceed the Yearly Value of one Thouſand Pounds above all Charges and Repri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zes, and alſo Goods and Chattels,<note place="margin">The Company may buy Goods and Chattels of what Nature or Value ſoever.</note> of what Value, Nature, or Kind ſoever; and alſo to Give, Grant, Alien, Aſſign and Diſpoſe of Mannors, Lordſhips, Meſſuages, Mills, Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters, Streams,<note place="margin">The Company may Sell their Lands, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and do all other Lawful Acts by the Name aforeſaid.</note> Rents, Services, Reverſions, Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments, Goods, Chattels, Liberties, Priviledges, Franchiſes and Juriſdictions, and alſo to Do and Exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cute all other Lawful Acts and Things whatſoever by the Name aforeſaid: <hi>And further,</hi> We have Given and Granted, and by theſe Preſents, for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, do Give and Grant unto all and every Subject and Subjects whatſoever, of Us, our Heirs, and Succeſſors Eſpecial Licence, Power, and Authority, to Give, Grant, Sell and Alien unto the ſaid Governour and Company,<note place="margin">Power given to all the Kings Subjects to Sell Land, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to the Company.</note> and their Succeſſors any Mannors, Lordſhips, Meſſuages, Mills, Waters, Streams, Rents, Services, Reverſions, Lands, Tenements, or Hereditaments whatſoever, ſo as the ſame do not exceed the Clear Yearly Value of One Thouſand Ponnds above all Charges and Reprizes whatſoever; and alſo Goods and Chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels, of what Nature or Value ſoever: <hi>And</hi> We do hereby for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, Give and Grant unto the ſaid Governour and Company, and their Succeſſors full Power and Authority to Make and Raiſe a Joynt-Stock,<note place="margin">The Company may raiſe what Stock they pleaſe and increaſe, manage or diminiſh the ſame as they ſhall think fit.</note> of any Value whatſoever, and the ſame Joynt-Stock to Order, Manage, and carry on from time to time for the purpoſes aforeſaid, and to receive the Benefit and Advantage of the ſame to the uſe of them, the ſaid Governour and Company, and their Succeſſors, according to ſuch Shares and Proportions as they, or any of them have, or ſhall have therein; And the ſame Joynt-Stock to Augment and Increaſe, or Reduce and Diminiſh from time to time, as they the ſaid Governour and Company, and their Succeſſors ſhall find moſt fitting and convenient. <hi>Provided always,</hi> That theſe Preſents, or any thing herein contained, ſhall not ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend, or be conſtrued to extend to diſcharge any of the Covenants or Proviſo's contained in the before-mentioned Letters Patents,<note place="margin">A Proviſo for keeping in Force the Patent Granted to Meſſ.</note> Granted to the ſaid <hi>Paul Cloudeſly, William Sherrard,</hi> and <hi>Peter Ducleu</hi> for the ſole Uſe and Benefit of the ſaid Invention of Making, Luſtrating, and Dreſſing of <hi>Allamodes, Renforces,</hi> and <hi>Luſtrings</hi> for the Term of Four<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teen Years: But that the ſame ſhall be, and continue in as full force to all Intents and Purpoſes, as if theſe Preſents had never been had, or made any thing herein before con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained to the contrary,<note place="margin">A Proviſo that the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany ſhall not have the Sole Benefit of the Invention for any longer Term than the Remainder of the <hi>14</hi> Years Granted in the Patent. But that after the End of that Term all Perſons may have Liberty.</note> notwithſtanding: <hi>Provided alſo,</hi> That this our Grant, or any thing herein contained, ſhall not extend, or be conſtrued to extend to the Granting the ſaid
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:134626:4" rendition="simple:additions"/>Governour and Company, the ſole Exerciſe and Benefit of the aforeſaid Invention for any <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> time than the Remainder of the ſaid Term of Fourteen Years, but that after the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                  <desc>••••</desc>
               </gap>tion of that Term, all Perſons who otherwiſe might Work the ſame, may have full <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                  <desc>••••</desc>
               </gap>ty ſo to do any thing herein before contained to the contrary notwithſtanding: <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap> likewiſe,</hi>
               <note place="margin">A Proviſo that this Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter ſhall not prejudice the Corporation of <hi>Weavers, London.</hi>
               </note> That nothing herein contained ſhall be prejudicial to the Corporation of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                  <desc>••••</desc>
               </gap>rs, <hi>London;</hi> and that all Perſons, their Apprentices and Servants that ſhall at any <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> hereafter Weave any of the ſaid <hi>Allamodes, Renforces,</hi> and <hi>Luſtrings,</hi> within the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                  <desc>••••</desc>
               </gap>s of the Charter of the ſaid Company, ſhall from time to time be bound Apprentices,<note place="margin">That all Perſons who ſhall Weave <hi>Allamodes, Renfor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces</hi> and <hi>Luſtrings</hi> within the Limits of the <hi>Weavers</hi> Charter ſhall be Apprentices or Members of that Company, Subject to the Ordinances of the ſame.</note> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Members of the ſaid Corporation, according to the purport of their Ordinances, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> to Government and Regulation of the ſaid Corporation of <hi>Weavers. <hi>And</hi>
               </hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>, We have Granted, and by theſe Preſents, for Us, Our Heirs and Sueceſſors, do <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> unto the ſaid Company, and their Succeſſors, That theſe our Letters Patents, or <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Enrollment thereof ſhall be in, and by all things Good, Firm, Valid, Sufficient,<note place="margin">That this preſent Charter ſhall in all things be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrued in Favour of the Company.</note> and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>tual in the Law, according to the true Intent and Meaning thereof, and ſhall be taken, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>rued, and adjudged in the moſt favourable and beneficial Senſe for the beſt Advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> of the ſaid Governour and Company, and their Succeſſors, as well in all Courts, as <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ere, and by all, and ſingular the Officers and Miniſters whatſoever, of Us, Our <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> and Succeſſors in this Our Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> and Dominion of <hi>Wales,</hi> any De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> or Incertainties in theſe Preſents contained, or any Matter, Cauſe, or thing what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> to the contrary, in any wiſe, notwithſtandnig. <hi>In Witneſs</hi> whereof, We have <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> theſe Our Letters to be made Patents, <hi>Witneſs</hi> Our ſelves at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>th Day of <hi>October,</hi> in the Fourth Year of our Reign. <hi>By Writ of Privy Seal,</hi>
            </p>
            <div type="clause">
               <head>A Clauſe out of an Act of Parliament, paſs'd in the Ninth and Tenth of <hi>William</hi> the Third, confirming the Charter of the <hi>Royal Lu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtring Company.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>AND whereas the King's moſt Excellent Majeſty, together with the late Queen (of Bleſſed Memory) by their Letters, Patents, or Charter under the Great Seal of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>d, bearing Date the Fifteenth Day of <hi>October,</hi> in the Fourth Year of Their ſaid <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>ies Reign, Reciting or taking Notice, that ſeveral Perſons therein Named did <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> the late King <hi>James</hi> the Second's Letters Patents, bearing Date the Three and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>ieth Day of <hi>November,</hi> in the Fourth Year of his Reign, for the Sole Uſe, Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>, and Benefit of a New Invention of Making, Dreſſing and Luſtrating of Silks, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Plain Black Alamodes, Renforces and Luſtrings, for the Term of Fourteen Years <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> the Day of the Date of the ſaid Letters Patents Their ſaid Majeſties did, for the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>raging ſo Commendable an Undertaking, Give, Grant, Conſtitute, Declare and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>point <hi>Thomas</hi> Earl of <hi>Pembrooke</hi> and <hi>Montgomery,</hi> and ſeveral other Perſons, in the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Charter mentioned and Contained, and ſuch others as ſhould be admitted into their <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>ety, to be from thenceforth One Body Corporate and Politick, in Deed and in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>, by the Name of the Royal Luſtring Company, for Making and Dreſſing of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>odes, Renforces, and Luſtrings in <hi>England,</hi> and by that Name to have Perpetual <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>eſſion, and divers and ſundry Priviledges, Liberties, Powers and Authorities, with <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Matters and Things in the ſaid Charter of Incorporation Mentioned and Expreſſed, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> thereby Granted to, and Veſted in the ſaid Company, and their Succeſſors, in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Sort, Manner, and Form as in and by the ſaid Charter, or Letters Patents, or In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>ent thereof is Mentioned and Expreſſed, and as thereby it more fully Appears: <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> foraſmuch as the ſaid Company have with great Labour and Charges brought the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Manufacture to Perfection, but by reaſon of the fraudulent Importation of Ala<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> and Luſtrings by divers Perſons, more regarding their own Intereſt, than the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> of <hi>England,</hi> their Duty to the King, and Obedience to the Laws of the Land,
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:134626:5" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                  <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="9" facs="tcp:134626:5" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                  <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="8" facs="tcp:134626:6" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                  <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="9" facs="tcp:134626:6" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                  <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="10" facs="tcp:134626:7" rendition="simple:additions"/>the ſaid Company have not Enjoyed the Benefit and Advantage intended them in and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> the ſaid Charter, but waſted their Time and Stock, in Conteſting with many Diff<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ties and Obſtructions, which they have met with ſince the Granting thereof: And it <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>pearing that the ſaid Manufacture cannot be ſo well Carried on, and Secured to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Kingdom, by any other Means as by Eſtabliſhing a Company to Carry on the ſa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Be it therefore Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That the aforeſaid Company, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> their Succeſſors, ſhall and may at all Times from henceforth Stand, Continue, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> a Body Politick and Corporate in Deed and in Name, by the Name of the Ro<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> Luſtring Company; And that the ſaid Company, and their Succeſſors ſhall and may <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Do, Uſe, Exerciſe and Enjoy all and ſingular the Liberties, Priviledges, Pow<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Authorities, Matters and Things in the ſaid Letters Patents, or Charter of Incorpor<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>on, mentioned to be Granted to them, as Amply, Fully, and Largely, to all Inte<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Conſtructions, and Purpoſes, as if the ſame were Word for Word Recited and Set d<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> at large in this preſent Act.</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.
<figure/>
            </trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
